selco.org 2010-06-16

# SELCO Community Credit Union - Privacy Policy

******  
**  
SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and   
SELCO Mortgage Company

**Our Privacy Pledge.** SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company respect the privacy of our customers. We recognize the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your personal financial information. This notice describes the privacy policy and practices followed by SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company. This notice explains what types of customer information we collect and under what circumstances we may share it. In this notice, the term "customer" includes members, customers, and clients of SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company.

**Customer Information We Collect.** We collect only relevant information about customers that is needed to establish and maintain accounts and services as the law allows or requires us to collect. We may collect personal and financial information about you (customer information), which is "nonpublic." The information we collect varies depending on the accounts and services you request and use. We collect information about you from the following sources:

> _**Application Information.**_ We retain personal information we receive from you on any application you provide for products and services we provide including deposit accounts, consumer and home loans, electronic services, financial consulting, securities, and insurance products. This information includes: name, address, social security number, birth date, phone number, employment and financial status, and credit history.
> 
> _**Your Transactions.**_ Any time you make a transaction involving any of the products or services offered by us, including transactions initiated by ATM, credit card, point-of-sale, telephone, Online Banking, and branch visit, we retain the transaction information, including: your account number, date, amount, source, and location of the transaction, and other pertinent transaction information.
> 
> _**Credit Reports and Marketing Information.**_ When we evaluate your application for an account or service, we may request a credit report about you from a consumer reporting agency. We retain the personal and credit history information about you and we may use it to evaluate future account service requests. From time to time, we also obtain demographic household information about members and potential members from marketing information firms. 
> 
> _**Online.**_ We obtain information online when you visit our web site, selco.org. This includes retaining information you provide us on any online application, Online Banking transaction or information you send to us by e-mail.

**Customer Information We Share.** In order to provide products and services to you, we share certain information about you between our affiliates, SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company, and third-party service providers. However, we only share information to the extent necessary to service your account or offer new services to you. If we share your information, it is with the goal of bringing you quality services, more choices and greater convenience. Information we may have about former customers is generally only shared or disclosed if necessary to enforce or administer an account or as required by law.

**Sharing Information Between Our Affiliated Companies.** SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company, provide products and services, including deposit and checking accounts, electronic services, credit cards, consumer and business loans, investments, insurance, and mortgage loans. We may share any application information (such as name, address, account number, social security number, etc.) and account information (such as type of accounts, account balances and transaction history) with our affiliates (and they with us) as necessary to carry out transactions you have requested or otherwise service your accounts. Each of our affiliates maintain the same privacy standards.

**Sharing Information with Third-Party Service Providers.** In order for us to conduct the operations of SELCO Community Credit Union, SELCO Group, Inc., and SELCO Mortgage Company, including servicing your account or processing your transactions, we need to share information with or between our affiliates and with our service providers, including: data processing companies; check, ATM and other payment processing companies; payment networks; loan service providers; insurance companies; collection agencies; credit reporting agencies; financial services companies; mortgage loan providers and brokers; securities brokerage and insurance companies; and financial service providers with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These service providers act on our behalf and have agreed in writing to keep the member information we provide to them confidential. We share the following categories of information with third-party service providers depending on the specific services provided:

  * Application information (name, address, account number, social security number, etc.)
  * Account information (type of accounts, account balances, and transaction history) 
  * Transaction information (dates, amounts, locations, and type of transaction)

We do not sell customer information nor share your account numbers with third-party marketers offering their products and services. While we may assist in offering financial products and services of our affiliate or other financial service providers, we control the customer information used to make such offers.

**Sharing Information as Legally Required or Permitted.** We may share any customer information of yours in response to a lawful request issued by a court, government agency or regulatory authority or as permitted by law in order to administer or enforce your account. We may also share our experience information about you with credit bureaus. Our reporting to credit bureaus is governed by the Fair Credit Reporting Act, which affords you the right to make sure that your credit bureau reports are accurate.

**Our Confidentiality and Security Safeguards.** We maintain strict policies and security controls to assure that customer information in our computer systems and files is protected. Our employees and agents are permitted access to customer information that they may need to perform their jobs and to provide service to you. Our employees and agents have access to such customer information as necessary to conduct a transaction or respond to your inquiries. All employees and agents are trained to respect customer privacy. No one except our employees and agents has regular access to our computer system and records storage. We have established internal security controls, including physical, electronic and procedural safeguards to protect the information you provide us and the information we collect about you. We will continue to review our internal security controls to safeguard customer information as we employ new technology in the future. 

**Online Privacy Protection.** At our web site, selco.org, you may apply for accounts and services and you may communicate with us using e-mail.

To protect the information you provide us online, we use multiple levels of security. Our Online Banking service and other portions of our web site(s) that collects information about you relies on industry standard, "Secure Sockets Layer" (SSL) encryption to secure your transaction information and communications. We will not ask you for personally identifiable information using standard e-mail. Generally, standard e-mails are not secured forms of communication.

When you _browse_ our web site(s), you do so anonymously; personally identifiable information about you is not collected. We do collect aggregate information about the pages visited. The aggregate information we collect is included for internal review so that we may improve the content of our web site(s). We use three methods for collecting and using information: 

  1. Through online forms on the web site(s) from data you provide when requesting products, services, or information from us. Some examples include loan applications, online chat, "contact us" forms, and other Internet communications from you and initiated by you. 
  2. By using small client-side files that reside on your computer, called cookies, of which we use two types: 
    1. Session cookies that expire at the end of your browsing session. Session cookies are used to store configuration and status information only _within_ a session. These cookies are stored in memory only while a user is visiting the web site(s) issuing the session cookie and are deleted from memory when the user closes the session. Session cookies are generally used to help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns and do not contain any personally identifiable or confidential information.
    2. Persistent cookies that expire at a date determined by us. These cookies are used to store configuration and status information between visits to a site. Persistent cookies are used by our Online Banking service to facilitate the processing of the transactions you conduct. Cookies within Online Banking are necessary for the security of your account. Like session cookies, persistent cookies do not contain any personally identifiable or confidential information. They can also be used to help you personalize your experience on our web site(s) should we choose to offer such a service.
  3. By logging your computer's IP address at the time of your visit to our web site(s). Your computer's IP address is the numerical address of your computer on the public Internet. Your computer's IP address is logged without any associated, personally identifiable information about you. We may use your computer's IP address for statistical purposes, troubleshooting, and through investigations of fraud or misuse.

**Protecting Children's Information Privacy.** We recognize that protecting children's identities and online privacy is important and that responsibility rests with us and with parents. Our youth savings programs include online marketing that has program information and education. We do not knowingly solicit or collect data from children online. In order to provide some youth program content, we may share certain information with third-party service providers. However, a child's personal information is not available to third parties. These providers are required to maintain the same privacy standards as us.

**Privacy Policy Inquiries.** If you have any questions about our privacy practices, contact us by calling toll free 800-445-4483, sending us an e-mail at [webmaster@selco.org](mailto://webmaster@selco.org), or writing to us at SELCO Community Credit Union, PO Box 7487, Eugene, OR 97401.

SELCO Community Credit Union [05/09]
